<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
<title type="text">Sarah Ing</title>
<generator uri="https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll">Jekyll</generator>
<link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml" />
<link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="" />
<updated>2015-01-10T19:26:50-06:00</updated>
<id>/</id>
<author>
  <name>Sarah Ing</name>
  <uri>/</uri>
  <email>sarahikeda@gmail.com</email>
</author>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Pair Programming]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/blog/readability-post/" />
  <id>/blog/readability-post</id>
  <published>2014-11-28T13:39:55-06:00</published>
  <updated>2014-11-28T13:39:55-06:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Sarah Ing</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>sarahikeda@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;phase-0-week-5&quot;&gt;Phase 0, Week 5&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the programming world, pair programming is a common occurrence. It’s the opportunity to work with another person, collaborating on code. How a session is run greatly depends on the pair’s preference, but usually involves one person driving (typing) and another navigating (directing the driver). Another way to pair is called ping pong pairing, which involves two people simultaneously working on the code with one writing the test and the other writing code to pass the other’s test.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the last five weeks of DBC, I’ve had the opportunity to pair with many people in my cohort on challenges. While initially nervous to expose my novice knowledge to others, I now find myself eager to jump right in with pairing challenges. I think this is greatly attributed to the openness, willingness and curiosity of my fellow DBC students. Being able to work on something together provides instant feedback and encouragement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been interesting to see different people’s thinking styles and discover the best way to work together. The biggest thing I’ve learned for a successful pairing session, is to have open communication. It’s important to check in with your pair, discuss strategy and make sure both people are comfortable. It’s also been crucial to talk through obstacles and one’s thought process. Admittedly, for me, this is not always easy. I like to think on my own when tackling problems but pair programming has made me realize that my partner is also an asset and can be key in pointing out something or making suggestions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With each pairing session, through the handy DBC tool, “Feedbackinator”, I’ve given and received feedback from my partner. When I first heard about this, it reminded me of the days of AOL Instant Messenger. In middle school, I remember someone in my school sent out a survey that could be filled out anonymously, to rate an individual on looks, intelligence and popularity. Thankfully the survey only made it to a couple people, but I do remember it creating drama because anonymous feedback led to some not-nice comments. On the contrary, though, Feedbackinator has been an ego-boosting, positive tool. I’ve learned from comments that I can be my worst critic because I’ll think I didn’t contribute enough, even though the feedback from my partner will say the contrary. Getting feedback like this is encouraging and also reinforces the importance of pair programming best practices (communication, communication, communication)!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/readability-post/&quot;&gt;Pair Programming&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Sarah Ing at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Sarah Ing&lt;/a&gt; on November 28, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thinking Style]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/blog/sample-post/" />
  <id>/blog/sample-post</id>
  <published>2014-11-14T13:39:55-06:00</published>
  <updated>2014-11-14T13:39:55-06:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Sarah Ing</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>sarahikeda@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;phase-0-week-2&quot;&gt;Phase 0, Week 2&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m a sucker for personality tests. I remember spending a large amount of time (too much) in middle school taking quiz after quiz, from chain e-mails to magazines. The draw for me has always been the value in reading the results. Each test, no matter the topic (“What does your favorite candy say about you?”, “What age do you actually act?”) provided a little more insight into myself so I could reflect and improve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of Dev Bootcamp we were asked to take a test on our thinking styles.Enthusiastically, I answered the questions, picking the most-fitting words from a set of attributes. Was I precise? Systematic? A people person?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The results of the test indicated that I am an: Abstract Random Thinker&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first though, upon reading this, was, “Oh crap.” That doesn’t sound like an ideal computer programmer! That means I’m not an orderly, sequential thinker. That means I’m all over the place! After taking another second to recover and reflect, I realized that being an abstract random thinker can also be an advantage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abstract thinkers flourish when they are able to brainstorm ideas and using their intuition, beyond what is actually on the surface. As an abstract random thinker, I enjoy listening to others and participating in group activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back on the past couple weeks of DBC (I can’t believe it’s the end of week 3 already!), I have certainly gotten to know myself better and seen some of these qualities come into play. I’ve really enjoyed the practice of pair programming for the opportunity to collaborate with others and discuss our ideas ahead of time. Working on one challenge at a time, has also required me to focus on one thing at a time, which is pinpointed as a potential weakness for abstract random.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DBC also introduced the concept of a fixed mindset vs. growth mindset, which I found useful while learning programming (especially at such a rapid pace). The growth mindset emphasizes that one’s ability is not limited and one can work on becoming better and stronger. Reflecting back on my abstract random thinking through this growth mindset, I am aware that I can play up my strengths while simultaneously improving upon my weaknesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All in all, the test was a fun throwback to my quiz-taking days and I found value in the results. I have a feeling that I’ll be coming out of DBC not just with programming skills, but with greater understanding of myself as a whole. Bring it on!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://web.cortland.edu/andersmd/learning/gregorc.htm&quot; class=&quot;btn&quot;&gt;Thinking Style &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/sample-post/&quot;&gt;Thinking Style&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Sarah Ing at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Sarah Ing&lt;/a&gt; on November 14, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>


  

<entry>
  <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fireside Chat]]></title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="/blog/hello-world/" />
  <id>/blog/hello-world</id>
  <published>2014-11-01T14:39:55-05:00</published>
  <updated>2014-11-01T14:39:55-05:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Sarah Ing</name>
    <uri></uri>
    <email>sarahikeda@gmail.com</email>
  </author>
  <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;phase-0-week-1&quot;&gt;Phase 0, Week 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To cap off the first week, Shereef Bishay, founder of DBC, held a fireside chat about the program. I found myself wow-ed by Shereef’s humility and came away from the talk with enough quotes to plaster my bedroom walls and refrigerator with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shereef introduced the concept of Kitchen Vs. Restaurant. You see, most of us slip into the habit of being the consumer. When you go to a restaurant you peruse the menu, select the most desirable item, and then wait to be served. Perhaps you’ll complain amount the amount of the time the dish takes to be prepared or have buyer’s envy when you see a neighboring diner eating a hearty steak while you’re pushing around salad leaves. The thing is, you’re in a passive role, waiting for things to happen to you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast, students who attend DBC are encouraged to join the kitchen. Get out your chef’s hat! Sharpen the knives! Start seasoning the soup (ok, you get it)! Basically, it’s a “Hey, take charge of your learning. Be the one creating.”With joining the kitchen ranks, students will then take owernship and invest in their own learning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alongside this key metaphor, is the encouragement to “expose your ignorance.” This makes me nervous but I am going to rise to the challenge. As a longtime practitioner of the fixed mindset, I shy away from this because frankly, I don’t want to appear unintelligent. What happens if everyone else is taking the new information in stride while I struggle with it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes down to it, I am responsible for taking note of what I do not understand and voicing this issue when it comes up. Being vulnerable and adapting to the growth mindset of embracing struggle, will pay off, not just at DBC, but in all aspects of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much like a fitness bootcamp instructor (without all the yelling and pushups, thank god), Shereef’s talk was an empowering one. I’m grateful to be a part of DBC and am excited to keep pushing myself to be the best developer possible. The most important thing is to keep embracing the challenges wholeheartedly, even when the going gets tough.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/blog/hello-world/&quot;&gt;Fireside Chat&lt;/a&gt; was originally published by Sarah Ing at &lt;a href=&quot;&quot;&gt;Sarah Ing&lt;/a&gt; on November 01, 2014.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
</entry>

</feed>